コードギアス反逆のルルーシュR2 TURN 22　皇帝　ルルーシュ
TURN 22　皇帝　ルルーシュ
ロイドさんとセシル
セシルさんはアーサーを抱いています
パソコンにむかうニーナに声をかけるミレイさん
あ
とリヴァルがピザをもってはいってきました
ブリタニア皇宮　エグゼリカ庭園
と馬に乗ったC.C.
ルルーシュの電話がなります
スザクでした
とジノ
テレビ画面にうつるルルーシュ
カンボジアではシュナイゼル コーネリア アーニャ カノンたちも
その映像をみていました
再びカンボジア
アッシュフォード学園に向かうルルーシュたち
中継するミレイさん
どよめく人たち
人々に手をふってこたえるルルーシュ
塀を乗り越えて叫ぶリヴァル
えっ
カレンとルルーシュ
と評議会の議員たちはルルーシュに好意的
神楽耶の映像がうつります
ん？
と顔をそらし涙を流す神楽耶
逃げるリヴァルとニーナ
と手をふるロイドさん
ルルーシュにも報告がいきます
そこへ通信がはいります
先日即位した　第99代ブリタニア皇帝　ルルーシュは
99th emperor Lelouch, who acceded
to the throne only a few days ago,
歴代皇帝陵の破壊を強行しました
has forced the destruction of the imperial
mausoleum holding the remains of past emperors.
貴族制度の廃止 財閥の解体
Following his abolition of the aristocracy,
breaking up of the financial cliques,
ナンバーズの解放に続き この行為に対しても
and liberation of the Numbers,
オデュッセウスをはじめとする元皇族たちは
Odysseus and other
former imperial family members...
新皇帝を支持しているようです
appear to be supporting even
these actions of the new emperor.
しかしブリタニア国内には
He's just amazing!
すっげえなあいつ
完全にブリタニアをつくりかえるつもりか
Does he really intend to
completely remake Britannia?
壊す のまちがいじゃないの？
Don't you mean destroy it?
ルルーシュのブリタニアへの怒りは本物だった？
Does this mean Lelouch
really did hate Britannia?
さからう勢力はすべてつぶしているし
He's eliminating any faction
which could oppose him.
超合衆国でもルルーシュ皇帝を支持するという声がほとんどです
Even in the U.F.N., most people are
expressing support for Emperor Lelouch.
やっぱりあいつは
I knew he was
really on our side!
俺たちの味方だったんだよ
民衆の 正義の味方という報道もありますしね
Some in the media are even calling
him the righteous hero of the masses.
報道といえば ディートハルトは？
Speaking of the media,
where's Diethard?
戻る気はないんでしょ
I doubt he plans
to come back here.
ああ シュナイゼルやコーネリアとともに身を隠した以上
No, not as long as he stays hidden
with Cornelia and Schneizel.
それよりさ どうするんだよ これから
Anyway, what do we do now?
これからって？
Now?
だってよぉブリタニアの皇帝がいいことやってんだからさあ
Well, I mean, the Britannian
emperor's doing good things now.
それは
That's...
いいや ちがう
No, he's not.
そうだな
You're right.
ルルーシュ皇帝の　いや ゼロの目的は
Emperor Lelouch, or Zero rather,
has one objective.
ルルーシュ ヴィ ブリタニアが命じる
Lelouch vi Britannia commands you!
おまえたちは私の奴隷となれ
All of you, become my slaves!
イエス　マイ　マジェスティ！
Yes, Your Majesty!
オール　ハイル　ルルーシュ！
All hail Lelouch!
皇帝陛下
Your Majesty, won't you let me
analyze that power just a teensy bit?
その力一度分析させてもらえませんかね
死にたいのか ロイドよ
Do you want to die, Lloyd?
ああ怖い怖い怖い
Ah! How frightening!
まったく
For heaven's sake.
ジェレミア ゴットバルト
Jeremiah Gottwald returns from
wiping out former Earl Rosenkreuz.
ただいま ローゼンロイツ元伯爵の討滅より帰還いたしました
ごくろうだった
Well done.
は
My Lord!
しかし 我ながら人望がないな
Still, I'm not very popular, am I?
こうも各地で貴族たちが反乱をおこすとは
The nobles are rebelling like
this in every area, aren't they?
既得権益が奪われるとならば　抵抗もする
People tend to resist when
you take away their vested interests.
だからこそわからせる必要がある
That's why we need to
make them understand.
血統書や過去の栄光にすがる
How foolish and pathetic it is to
cling to pedigrees and past glories.
愚かさとあさましさを
Sekai no owari de
At the end of the world
Umareta hikari
The light that's born
Ima kaze no naka
Now blows in the wind
Kireigoto dake jaa ikirenai
Pretty words alone won't sustain you
Yasashisa dake jaa iyasenai
Kindness alone won't heal you
Ubawareta nowa nanda
What is it that was stolen from you
Kawaranai sekai de
In this unchanging world
Kikoetekita nowa nanda
What is it that you hear
Shikisai no uta
A song of color
Everything is bright...
Kudakechitta yume wo
Let our crumbled dreams resound
Asu no hate ni hibikaseru you ni
At the edge of tomorrow
Sekai no owari de
At the end of the world
Umareta hikari
The light that's born
Bokura hitotsu ni
Becomes one with us
Ima kaze no naka
Now blows in the wind
EMPEROR LELOUCH
よかったのかい？
You think this is all right?
よかったんですか
Do I think what is all right?
Um... Well, you know...
う～んだってさあ シュナイゼル殿下とコーネリア皇女殿下はどっかにいっちゃったし
The way Prince Schneizel and
Princess Cornelia have disappeared.
一応こっちが神聖ブリタニア帝国なんでしょ
This is still the Holy Britannian
Empire, you know?
そうなんですよねえ
Yes, you have a point.
それにスザクくんたちがやろうとしていることを知ってしまったら
And if they realized what Suzaku
and the others are doing, then...
いつのまにかこっちがパーツになってたってことかなあ
I wonder if we've become parts to
be used without even realizing it.
そういえば知ってました？
By the way, did you know?
何を？
About what?
皇帝陛下ってスザク君と同じ学校にかよっていたんですよ
His Majesty and Suzaku
went to the same school.
へえ～ミレイやニーナくんの
Really?
Milly and Nina's school?
帰りは夜になるから
I'll be back tonight.
取材？
Covering something?
会議よ
A conference.
皇帝を　ルルーシュを支持するかどうか？
To decide if we support His Majest...
Lelouch, I mean?
それもあるけど
That's part of it. Area 11...
Sorry, I mean Japan...
このエリア１１　ううん　日本か
ここがブリタニアじゃなくなったから本土に戻るかどうかって話
It's about whether or not we should go back to
the homeland now that this isn't part of Britannia.
でも
But...
うちももう貴族じゃなくなったしねえ
Yeah. It's not like my
family's nobility anymore.
ルルーシュが
Lelouch is...
スト～ップ！
Stop!
その話題はさあ ここではやめておかない？
Can we stop talking
about this right here?
はらへった～ニーナ
Man, I'm hungry.
Here, Nina.
ごめんね リヴァル
Sorry, Rivalz.
いいからいいから
Forget it, okay?
外には出んなよ学園の中なら安全だ
Don't go out.
You're safe here in the school.
ありがとう
Thanks.
フレイヤをつくったせいで
I never thought all those countries would
target me for having made the F.L.E.I.J.A.
いろんな国から狙われることになるなんて
思ってもいなかった
Britannian Imperial Palace
EXELICA GARDEN
即位そうそう
ルルーシュ皇帝は歴史に名を残した
ブリタニアの文化を破壊したんだから
Soon after ascending the throne,
Emperor Lelouch's name became historic.
Because he destroyed Britannian culture.
序の口だよ まだ
The real work is yet to come.
これから俺は多くの血を流す
I am about to spill
a sea of blood.
虐殺皇女の名がかすみ
Enough blood to wipe all memory of the
massacre princess from peoples' minds.
人々の記憶から消えさるほどに
ルルーシュ 君は
Lelouch, are you saying?
ユフィだけじゃないナナリーも
It wasn't just Euphy.
It was Nunnally, too.
俺たちは失った失いすぎた
We've both lost much.
Far, far too much.
それでも明日をむかえるためには
But to advance toward the future,
we need to take over the world.
まず世界征服から
ふふっ 口にすると笑ってしまう
Just saying it makes me laugh.
だが　やるつもりなのだろう おまえたちは
Yet you're both intent
on doing it, aren't you?
ああゼロレクイエムのために
Yes. For the sake
of the Zero Requiem.
イエス　ユア　マジェスティ
Yes, Your Majesty.
で どうするんです？陛下
Well then, what will you do about
the problem at hand, Your Majesty?
例の問題は
ふむそのためにブリタニアを手に入れたわけだから
Yes. I took over
Britannia for that, but...
本当なのかシュナイゼルが考えていること
Is it true?
About what Schneizel is thinking?
ああ例の情報と
Yes. Considering that intelligence,
カンボジアのトロモ機関がブリタニアから離反したという事実
and that the Tromo Agency in
Cambodia has cut ties with Britannia...
これをかさねたとき
When you take everything into account,
it leaves us with only one reality.
みえてくる真実は　ひとつしかない
シュナイゼルが行動を起こす前に
We have to move the plan to the
next phase before Schneizel can act.
計画を次の段階に進めねば
どうした？
What?
陛下
Majesty!
It's the Knights of the Round!
ナイトオブラウンズが！
ナイオトブワンを先頭にこちらにむかってきます
They're approaching,
with the Knight of One in the lead!
ラウンズの機体は　確認できただけでも　４機はいます
We can only confirm
four of the Rounds among them.
また　その直属部隊までが
They're accompanied
by their personal forces!
我らはシャルル陛下に忠誠をちかった存在とビスマルク
We swore our loyalty
to Emperor Charles!
王位の簒奪など 認められぬ！
We will not recognize
this usurper to the throne!
ん？迎撃部隊？
An interceptor?
But only one?
しかしたった１機で
この　ランスロット アルビオンなら
Lancelot Albion will be enough.
えっ？おいかけきれない
I can't track it!
まさか やられた？
It can't be!
He got me already?!
うん？アルビオンか
The Albion?!
これが第9世代ナイトメアの　枢木スザ
A 9th generation Knightmare Frame,
which means...
Suzaku Kururugi!
目をさませ　スザク！
Wake up, Suzaku!
今ならまだもどれるぞ！
You can still come back to us!
戻る？逆だよ ジノ
Come back?
You've got it backwards, Gino.
君がブリタニアに忠誠を誓うなら僕の仲間になるべきだ
If you've sworn loyalty to Britannia,
then you belong on my side!
あっ
それとも　ブリタニアに反旗を翻すつもりか？
Or do you intend
to stand against Britannia?
うっ ブリタニアに
Against Britannia...
枢スザク！貴様の目的は
Suzaku Kururugi!
I heard your objective was
to become the Knight of One!
ナイトオブワンになることときいた
しかし
However!
I am the only Knight of One!
私こそが唯一のナイトオブワン
貴様ごときに譲る道理はない！
And I have no intention of giving up
that title to the likes of you!
自分はナイトオブワンすら超える存在
I am the Knight of Zero,
a rank that surpasses the Knight of One!
ナイトオブゼロです
プライドなき　名前など！
A title without
a shred of pride!
番組の途中ですが
We interrupt our programming for this live
relay from the Holy Britannian Empire.
ここで　神聖ブリタニア帝国からの中継をお伝えします
あれは ランスロット！
That's... Lancelot!
エナジーウィングを
With energy wings?
相手はビスマルクか
And it's fighting Bismarck.
スザクとビスマルク
どうしてランスロットの軌道が
How can he know
Lancelot's flight path?!
わがギアスは未来をよむ
My Geass allows me
to see the future!
まただ
Again!
この力　マリアンヌ様以外につかうことがあろうとはな！
Lady Marianne was the only one I've
ever needed to use this power against!
動きをよまれる？しかし
He can predict my movements?
Even so...
スザク
Suzaku! This video is being broadcast
to the world, as we planned.
予定通りこの映像は世界中に流している
ああゼロレクイエムのためにも
Right. For the sake of
the Zero Requiem, I can't lose!
負けるわけにはいかない！
だからおまえは　生きろ！
That's why I'm ordering you to live!
イエス　ユア　マジェスティ！
Yes, Your Majesty!
帝国最強の騎士は！我が名とともに！
My name will always be linked...
with the title of mightiest knight in the empire!
なっ なに？なんだ？これは
Wh-What?!
What is this?
Is it the machine's abilities...
機体性能か？
それとも枢木の
or is it Kururugi's?
スザク尋常な精神力ではない
Suzaku...
Your will power is extraordinary.
俺がかけた　生きろというギアス
Turning my Geass command
to live into an unexpected weapon.
それを逆手にとって
やっぱりたいしたものだよ おまえは
You are truly a man
to be reckoned with!
軌道をよまれていても　これなら！
Even if you can predict my movements,
if I do this!
正面！なめられたものだ
Head on?! You insult me!
マリアンヌ様
Lady Marianne!
ナ ナイトオブワンが敗れた
The...
The Knight of One has fallen!
私は ブリタニア人なのか？
Am I a Britannian?
それとも
And if I'm not...
then what am I fighting for?!
なんのために戦えばいいんだ！
全世界に告げる
- To the people of the world!
- Lelouch!
ルルーシュ
今の映像で私が名実ともに　ブ
I think the video you've just seen...
リタニアの支配者とおわかりいただけたことと思う
should convince you all that I am truly
Britannia's ruler in name and reality.
そのうえでわが神聖ブリタニア帝国は
Not only that,
but the Holy Britannian Empire...
超合集国への参加を表明する
declares its desire to join
the United Federation of Nations!
それって
Meaning...
ブリタニアが仲間になる
Britannia will be on our side?
ほらみろ！やっぱりあいつは
See, I told you!
He's on our side!
俺たちの味方だ！
交渉には　枢木スザクをはじめとする武官は立ち会わせない
CAMBODIA
すべて超合集国のルールに従おう
For the negotiations, I will not be accompanied...
...by Suzaku Kururugi or any military officers.
I shall follow all rules of the U.F.N.
ただし　交渉の舞台は
However, the site
of the negotiations...
現在ブリタニアと超合集国の中立地帯となっている
shall be the nation which is neutral between
Britannia now and the U.F.N.: Japan.
日本　アッシュフォード学園を
Specifically, at Ashford Academy.
指定させていただこう
ええ～？！
This is 1-4-4. North wing, clear.
兄上 何かあったのですか
Brother, has something happened?
私たちに賛同できないという人が　ここから逃げ出してね
A person who couldn't
approve of us has fled.
急がねばならなくなったよダモクレスを
We need to hurry up
and deploy Damocles.
本当にそれしかないのですか
Is that really our
only option now?
選ぶのは　世界かな
That's up to
the world to decide.
ルルーシュ本当に大丈夫なのか
Lelouch, are you sure
about this?
私と数人のSPだけで
Just me and a few SPs?
こちらはお願いしにいく立場だ
We're going there
asking for a favor.
民主主義に参加させてほしいってね
To participate in
their democracy.
へぇ
Oh?
みんな好きだろ民主主義を
And we know how everyone
loves democracy, don't we?
こちらが　ブリタニア皇帝ルルーシュ陛下が指定された
We're coming to you
from Ashford Academy,
the site designated by His Majesty
Lelouch, emperor of Britannia.
アッシュフォード学園です
本日ここで　ブリタニア帝国の
It is here that deliberations...
超合集国加盟を審議する評議会が
on allowing the Britannian Empire
to join the U.F.N. will be held today.
ブリタニアの皇帝専用機です
It's the Britannian
emperor's plane!
ルルーシュ ほんとうに
Lelouch, is it really you?
あっ失礼しました
Sorry about that! Emperor Lelouch has
just landed inside the school grounds.
ただいまルルーシュ陛下が学園内に降り立ちました
あれが正義の皇帝！ルルーシュ様
It's Lelouch,
the emperor of justice!
まだ少年じゃないか皇帝陛下ぁ～！
- He's just a kid!
- Your Majesty!
ルルーシュ！教えてくれよ！ルルーシュ
Lelouch!
Lelouch, please tell me!
おまえは今までどうして俺に
Why didn't you ever tell me?!
こら！ご無礼であろう!ブリタニアの皇帝陛下に
Hey!
はなしてくれよ
- How dare you disrespect the Britannian emperor like that!
- Lemme go!
だって　だって友達なんだよ！
But... But we're friends!
あいつは！ルルーシュは！
He's... Lelouch is!
おい
この
Hey!
すみませんすぐにどきますから！
Why, you!
He's sorry!
We'll leave right now!
リヴァル　行こう
Rivalz, let's go!
ルルーシュ　どうして
Lelouch, why...
はじめまして
How do you do?
黒の騎士団所属の　紅月カレン隊長ですね
You're Capt. Kallen Kouzuki of
the Black Knights, are you not?
はい私が案内させていただきます
Yes.
I'm here to escort you.
少し　遠回りしてもいいでしょうか
Could we take the
long way round, please?
え
いささか緊張していてね
I'm feeling a bit anxious.
I'd like to take a little walk.
歩きたい気分なんです
わかりました
I understand.
ゼロは ルルーシュはここで何か仕込むつもりか？
Is Zero... Is Lelouch
here to try something?
無理だ
機情のシステムはすべて停止させた
Impossible. The O.S.I.'s systems
are completely down now.
警護のものたちにはゴーグルを着用を徹底させてある
We've also ordered
all guards to wear goggles.
ギアス対策は問題ない
There are no problems with
our Geass countermeasures.
紅月からは　自分がギアスにかかっていると思われる場合は
Kouzuki said that if we think
he's used his Geass on her,
狙撃してほしいとの申し出もうけている
she wants us
to use the snipers.
心配しすぎだろ
Are you being
too cautious about this?
あいつは仲間になりにきたんだからよ
He's come here to be
friends with us!
懐かしいな
Nostalgic, isn't it?
私 あなたには感謝してる
I'm... I'm grateful to you.
あなたがいなければ
If it weren't for you,
I would have died in the Shinjuku ghetto.
私たちはシンジュクゲットーで死んでいた
黒の騎士団もなかった
There never would have
been any Black Knights.
私はうれしかった
I was glad.
ゼロに必要とされたことも光栄で　誇らしくて
Proud and honored
to be needed by Zero.
でも ゼロがルルーシュだってわかって
But... When I learned you were Zero,
I didn't understand anymore.
わけがわからなくなって
それでも　ブリタニアとと戦うあなたをみて
Even so, the man I saw
fighting against Britannia...
そんなあなたがスザクと手をくんで
Now you've joined up with Suzaku.
今度は何がやりたいの？
What do you want to do now?
力がほしいだけ？
Do you just want power?
Or is it status you seek?
地位がお望み？
それとも　これもゲームなの？
Or... Is this just
another game to you?
ブラックリベリオンのとき
Back during the Black Rebellion,
Ohgi told me to protect you.
扇さんはあなたを守れと言った
私の お兄ちゃんの夢を継ぐものだって
He said you could make my
big brother's dream come true.
ルルーシュ
あなたは私のことをどう思っているの？
Lelouch...
What am I to you?!
どうしてイカルガで私に
Why did you tell me to live
back aboard the Ikaruga?!
君は生きろと言ったのよ？！
さようなら ルルーシュ
Goodbye, Lelouch.
最高評議会は体育館で行う予定です
The supreme council is scheduled
to meet in the gymnasium.
さようなら カレン
Goodbye, Kallen.
超合集国最高評議会議長　皇神楽耶殿
Chairman Kaguya Sumeragi
of the U.F.N. supreme council.
我が神聖ブリタニア帝国の超合集国への加盟を認めていただきたい
I would like for the Holy Britannian Empire to
participate in the United Federation of Nations.
ゼロ様
Master Zero.
各合集国代表　３ぶんの２以上の賛成が必要だと
Do you understand that participation...
is dependent upon a two-thirds majority
vote of U.F.N. members?
わかっていますか？
もちろんそれが民主主義というものでしょう
Of course. It's a democratic
way of doing it, isn't it?
そうですね
Indeed, it is.
やはりこれは失礼ではないかな
This is a bit rude, isn't it?
ブリタニアの悪行は先代シャルル皇帝のせいかと
It was Charles, the former emperor, who
ordered Britannia's misdeeds, was it not?
ギアス対策かしかし これでギアスのことは
Geass countermeasures, huh?
But now it's clear that only the core
members of the Black Knights...
黒の騎士団の中核メンバーと神楽耶しか知らないとはっきりしたな
and Kaguya know about Geass.
あなたの狙いはなんですか？悪逆皇帝ルルーシュ
What are you after,
treacherous Emperor Lelouch?
これは異なことを
I'm surprised at you.
今のブリタニアは　あなたたちにとってもよい国では？
Isn't Britannia as it is now
a better country for you all?
はたしてそうかな？
Is it?
超合集国の決議は多数決によってきまる
U.F.N. resolutions are
determined by majority vote.
この投票権は　各国の人口に比例している
Voting rights are apportioned according
to each member nation's population.
中華連邦が崩壊した今
With the breakup of the Chinese Federation,
the most populous nation in the world now...
世界最大の人口を誇る国家は
ブリタニアだ
is Britannia.
ここでブリタニアが超合集国に加盟すれば
If we allow Britannia
to join the U.F.N. now...
過半数の票をルルーシュ皇帝がもつことになる
You will have more than 50%
of the votes, Emperor Lelouch.
つまり　超合集国は事実上
In short, you would, in fact,
be usurping control of the U.F.N.
あなたにのっとられてしまうことになるのでは？
そうか！
やっぱりあいつは悪人かあ！
I get it!
He really is a bad guy, after all!
あなたって　本当におバカさんだったのねえ
You really are terribly dim,
aren't you?
なんだと！？
どうなんだ？！
Say what?!
What about it, Emperor Lelouch?!
違うというのなら この場でブリタニアという国を割るか
If you say we're wrong,
we want you to either divide up Britannia...
投票権を人口比率の２０％までさげさせていただきたい
or else limit your voting
representation to 20%.
神楽耶どの
Chairman Kaguya,
I have one question for you.
ひとつ質問してもいいだろうか
なんでしょうか？
And that is?
世界を統べる資格とはなんですか
What is the qualification
for controlling the world?
矜持です人が人を統べるのは
Dignity. The dignity for people
to govern one another.
いい答えだ
Good answer.
あなたはやはり優秀だ
You truly are astute.
しかし　私の答えは違う
However, my answer is different.
きかせていただけますか
May I ask what that is?
壊す覚悟
The willingness to destroy.
壊す？
世界も自分自身すらも！
Destroy?
The world... and even yourself!
いけない！
やっぱり何か仕込んで
Oh, no!
He is up to something, after all!
上からランスロットがおりてきました
しまった！
Dammit!
皇帝陛下に対する無礼は許しません！
I will not allow this
affront to His Majesty!
索敵班!何をしていた！
Where the hell were
our perimeter guards?!
もうしわけありません！
Sorry, sir! He just suddenly
launched from underwater!
海中からいきなり
脅迫するつもり?
Is it a threat?! Will he use
violence on the representatives?
代表達を暴力で
アッシュフォード学園に急げ！
Get to Ashford Academy!
Save Lady Kaguya!
神楽耶様を救い出すんだ
ブリタニア軍が移動を開始しました
The Britannian forces
have started to move!
何?
黄海から日本の領海にはいりつつあります
What?!
They're moving from international
waters into Japanese waters!
ここで奇襲とは
A surprise attack here?!
超合集国への加盟も　学園を指定したのも
Participating in the U.F.N.
and choosing the school as the site...
すべては自分自身を囮とするため
It was all to use
himself as a decoy!
しかし　国際的な信用を裏切ってまで
But now he's betrayed the trust
of the international community.
いいえもはや信用などいらないということでしょ
No. He's saying he
doesn't need it now.
やっぱり　目的は独裁政治
So, his objective
is a dictatorship.
貴族制を廃止しながら
A man who continues to call himself an
emperor after abolishing the aristocracy...
自らは皇帝を名乗り続けた男
そうだ
ゼロは ルルーシュは世界の敵となった
You're right. Zero is now...
Lelouch is now the enemy of the world!
ひけ！ここはひくんだ紅月君
Retreat!
Get out of here, Kouzuki!
ルルーシュを倒すのは私です
I'll be the one
to take down Lelouch!
それに　あのランスロットと戦えるのは紅蓮しか
Besides, the Guren is the only unit
that can oppose the Lancelot!
ここで戦闘になれば各国代表も失うことになる
If you fight here,
every nation will lose its representative!
いきなり国の指導者がいなくなったら
If every nation suddenly
loses its leader, then!
でも！天子様だって危ないのに！
But Her Majesty is in danger, too!
わかっている！
I know that!
But your enemy is Lelouch!
だが　相手はルルーシュだ
人質を殺す覚悟があってこその行動
It's clear he's prepared
to kill the hostages here!
ここは各国の判断を待たねば
If we don't wait for the
decision of every nation here,
超合集国そのものが崩壊する
the U.F.N. itself will collapse!
勝つのはブリタニアとなってしまう！
And that would leave
Britannia victorious!
スザク
Suzaku...
さあ　皇議長
Now then, Chairman Sumeragi...
投票を再開していただこう
I'd like to resume the vote.
わがブリタニアを受け入れるか否か
Will you allow Britannia
to join or not?
このようなやり口
Using these methods?!
認めざるをえないはずですが
You have no choice but
to allow it, don't you?
さあ　民主主義をはじめようか
Now then, shall we begin
this democratic process?
うっ
ルルーシュもスザクも何考えてんだよ
Lelouch and Suzaku!
What are they both thinking?!
世界を全部敵にまわして！
They're declaring war
on the whole world!
検問？
もう私のことは放っておいて！
A roadblock?
Forget about me!
You'll just end up getting involved, too!
あなたまで巻き込まれちゃう！
ほうっておけるわけないだろう！
I can't just leave you!
ミレイちゃんに頼まれたから？だったら
As a favor to Milly?!
In that case...
バカ！友達だから
No, you idiot!
Because I'm your friend!
おめでと～あはっあはっあはっ
Congratulations!
最重要人物を確保しました
Priority target 1 has been captured.
すべて　陛下の予測されたとおりです
It all went as you predicted,
Your Majesty.
よしくれぐれも丁重にな
Good.
Treat her with courtesy, please.
あっそれと いっしょにいるであろう学生は置いていけ
Oh, one more thing.
Let the student I assume
was with her go free.
イエス　ユア　マジェスティ
Yes, Your Majesty!
陛下！アマロンから緊急入電です
Majesty!
Emergency dispatch
from the Avalon!
どうした？
帝都　ペンドラゴンにあれが
What is it?
The capital, Pendragon...
It's been!
しまった！先手を打たれたか
Dammit! He's struck first!
消失半径は約 １００キロメートル
The radius of annihilation is
approximately... 100 kilometers.
フレイヤによるものと思われます
I think it was caused
by a F.L.E.I.J.A. Also...
それと 上空に　巨大な要塞でしょうか
There's a giant fortress
in the sky above it.
全長３キロメートルはあります
With a total length
of 3 kilometers.
いったい何が
What's happened?
ルルーシュやはり君の推測通り
Lelouch!
It's just as you guessed!
ああ一次製造分のフレイヤ弾頭
Yes. No doubt the stock of F.L.E.I.J.A.
warheads they initially produced...
まちがいなくトロモ機関が開発していた
have been loaded aboard the sky fortress Damocles
which was developed by the Tromo Agency.
天空要塞ダモクレスに搭載されているはずだが
皇室専用チャンネルを知っているのは とC.C.
The only one who would know
the imperial private channel is...
モニターにあらわれたシュナイゼル
他人を従えるのは気持ちがいいかい？ルルーシュ
Does it feel good to subdue
other people, Lelouch?
シュナイゼル
Schneizel.
フレイヤ弾頭はすべて私が回収させてもらった
I've taken custody of
all the F.L.E.I.J.A. warheads.
ブリタニア皇帝に弓をひくと？
Are you drawing your bow
against the Britannian emperor?
残念だが　私は君を皇帝と認めていない
I'm afraid I don't
recognize you as emperor.
なるほど皇帝にふさわしいのは自分だと
I see.
I suppose you think you
are better suited to be emperor.
違うな
No.
You're mistaken, Lelouch.
間違っているよ ルルーシュ
ん？
ブリタニアの皇帝にふさわしいのは
The one best suited
to rule Britannia...
彼女だ
is her.
N...!
ナナリー！！
Nunnally!
お兄様　スザクさん
Big brother... Suzaku... I...
わたくしは お二人の敵です
I am now your enemy.
Dakuse wa oni
This corrupt world is filled with demons
Seigi wa nanzo to
What is justice?
Tou mae ni aragae yo
Resist, don't just question
Akutoku no hana
The flower of evil
Gizen no yume
Dreams of hypocrisy
Mishi me niwa me wo sashi
Give your gaze to the eyes that see them
Sei mo ja mo wakatareru koto nashi
The line between right and wrong cannot be known
Hikari wa tae taiji no you ni
Light is gone, and you slumber
Kimi wa nemuru yami no shikyuu
Like an unborn child in the womb of darkness
Kodoku koso itooshii
Isolation is what you love
Yui-itsu no mikata to naru darou
It will probably be your only ally
Hitori hitori chishio ni mamire
One by one, stained with the tide of blood
Kono jidai ni umare ochita
You were born into this era
Erabareshi oujira yo
Oh, chosen princes
Tatakai koso shukuen
Battle shall be your banquet
Aa ware wa uruwashii zenchi
Oh, I am graceful omniscience
Ai no haha
The loving mother
Kimi wo umu
Who bore you
Kono chichi ni hagukumishi mono wa
The ones who were raised on my breast
Jigoku no harakara
Are your brethren in hell
Mokushi no in
The mark of apocalypse
Shinri wa nanzo to
What is truth
Shirimosezu uzumoreshi intoku no tane
A seed of secrecy buried where no one knows
Moroha no ken
A double-edged sword
Nuku ha niwa ha wo muke
Turn its blade upon the unsheathed blade
Mamorubeki mono dake wo shinjite
Believe only in what you must protect
Aru ga mama ni kimi wa
And in your own way
Kimi wo hanate
You'll set yourself free
ナナリー八年前のあの日から
Nunnally... Ever since that day 8
years ago when we were abandoned,
俺には生きるための目的が　縁が必要だったんだろ
I've needed some reason to go on living.
なら　俺は今また存立基盤を
よって立つべきものを失うのか
Before I realized it, you became my guidepost.
それとも
Perhaps you became my foundation.
Perhaps it's linked with something which
Suzaku and Kallen feel so strongly about.
ルルーシュだ
今週も楽しんでくれてありがとう
いつも応援してくれているみんなにご覧のプレゼントを送る
If that's true, must I once more have
to lose the basis for my existence?
こちらのケータイサイトから応募してほしい
本日中の受付だ
Or else,
do I now have to!
もちろん　特製待受けもあるぞ
それでは諸君　来週もお楽しみに
SCHNEIZEL'S GUISE